<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>National Geographic Society Newsroom</title>
	<atom:link href="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org</link>
	<description>Ideas and Insight From National Geographic</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 18:48:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">140149203</site>	<item>
		<title>Students Reflect on Photo Camp Experience with National Geographic Explorer Tara Roberts</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/19/students-reflect-on-photo-camp-experience-with-national-geographic-explorer-tara-roberts/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=students-reflect-on-photo-camp-experience-with-national-geographic-explorer-tara-roberts</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/19/students-reflect-on-photo-camp-experience-with-national-geographic-explorer-tara-roberts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karen Cumberland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In July 2022, the National Geographic Society hosted a five-day Photo Camp in Key Largo, Florida where 20 young people—including members of Youth Diving With a Purpose (U.S.) and Centro Comunitario de Buceo Embajadores y Embajadoras del Mar (Ambassadors of the Sea Community Diving Center) based in Costa Rica—learned photography skills with guidance from National...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In July 2022, the National Geographic Society hosted a five-day Photo Camp in Key Largo, Florida where 20 young people—including members of Youth Diving With a Purpose (U.S.) and Centro Comunitario de Buceo Embajadores y Embajadoras del Mar (Ambassadors of the Sea Community Diving Center) based in Costa Rica—learned photography skills with guidance from National Geographic Explorers </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/impact/article/jahawi-bertolli-telling-the-story-of-the-ocean"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jahawi Bertolli</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/impact/article/tara-roberts-diving-with-a-purpose"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tara Roberts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Throughout the week, Photo Camp students reflected on themes of cultural preservation and ocean conservation in the Florida Keys. They also built their photography skills as they snorkeled and explored the coastal waters and visited the Higgs Beach slave memorial in Key West.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, Roberts, who was named the 2022 Rolex National Geographic Explorer of the Year in June, reconnected with three participants––Kennedy Lucas, Damien Davis, and Bo Visty––and they reflected on lessons learned during their Photo Camp experience, and shared future goals. </span></p>
<p><b>Tara Roberts: Did you have an “ah-ha” moment during the camp?</b></p>
<p><b>Kennedy Lucas:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I remember getting up super-early one morning, and I am not a morning person so it was super-difficult but I got up because my friends and I wanted to take pictures of the sunrise. I was looking around when I saw a bird on a fence. As I was getting closer, I took this photo where the bird’s foot was kind of stuck in the air right as it was about to walk and showed intent through that photograph. I was like ‘this is it!’ From that point forward, I was looking for good stories rather than good composition opportunities.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_216482" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-216482" style="width: 720px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-medium wp-image-216482" src="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Kennedy-Lucas-720x534.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="534" srcset="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Kennedy-Lucas-720x534.jpg 720w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Kennedy-Lucas-1140x846.jpg 1140w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Kennedy-Lucas.jpg 1284w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-216482" class="wp-caption-text">“An early bird” photographed during National Geographic Photo Camp Key Largo by student Kennedy Lucas. Photo by Kennedy Lucas/National Geographic.</figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Damien Davis:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> My favorite night at the camp was when my friends and I went to take pictures of the moon and the lightning. The process of setting up a shot and then waiting for the exposures to happen was my favorite thing. During that time you would always find something new as you wait. With astrophotography, you don’t necessarily know what you are going to get and that is truly fascinating to me which is why I am saving up for a telescope now.</span></p>
<p><b>Tara: Do you think the assignments changed the way you see yourself or others in any way?</b></p>
<p><b>Bo:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I’m noticing the details in the way people look in the way that everyone’s face would make a great photograph. It’s less about physical traits and more about people’s beauty through a camera lens.</span></p>
<p><b>Kennedy:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> At first I was looking at taking a photo of a landscape, an animal, or something else, and now I want to capture emotions. Whether it’s through portraiture or taking photos of nature I really want to capture the more abstract feelings that will then transfer to us when we view the photographs.</span></p>
<p><b>Damien:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I love seeing everyone’s different thought processes when they look at the photos. For example, three different people could look at a photo and they would tell you three different stories. I like seeing how people think about that and how their life experiences influence it because I think it shows that we all have a story to tell.</span></p>
<p><b>Tara: Was there a story that you tried to tell about yourself in one of the photographs? If you did that, how did people respond to that? Did they see or hear the story you were trying to share?</b></p>
<p><b>Kennedy:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Often as photographers, I think we get so into the details that we get emotionally connected to the shots and we want the best story to be told. But when we show our work to other people we can look more at the bigger picture and the story we tried to capture at that moment. I think that is special because we are exposed to new perspectives and new stories which help us realize we all have a different interpretation of things.  </span></p>
<p><b>Bo:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I’m not used to taking photos and then having to fit them together into a collection. So, I was a bit inexperienced on that front. I took some good photos but when I had to compile them into a story it was difficult. So, I spent an entire day taking photos of all the mentors to use as my final collage and my favorite photo was of Ms. Tara laughing which fit perfectly into my collage. I think through that process of realizing what I needed, it taught me about how to get what I need to fit the story in my mind. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_216483" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-216483" style="width: 720px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-216483" src="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-720x540.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="540" srcset="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-720x540.jpg 720w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-1140x855.jpg 1140w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-1467x1100.jpg 1467w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/PC-22-KL-D4-BVI-020-720x540@2x.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-216483" class="wp-caption-text">A portrait of National Geographic Explorer Tara Roberts taken by National Geographic Photo Camp Key Largo by student Bo Visty. Photo by Bo Visty/National Geographic.</figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Damien:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I was struggling to take a photo when one of my friends told me “I really like this photo” and I was like “why?” because I was so frustrated by it. I ended up putting it in my final collage. I didn’t capture what I originally intended but I was really happy with the final result and got that perspective only afterward.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_216484" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-216484" style="width: 720px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-216484" src="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-720x540.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="540" srcset="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-720x540.jpg 720w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-1140x855.jpg 1140w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-1467x1100.jpg 1467w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Damien-Davis-720x540@2x.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-216484" class="wp-caption-text">A Key Largo nightscape taken by National Geographic Photo Camp student Damien Davis. Photo by Damien Davis/National Geographic.</figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Tara: What does it mean to you to say you were a participant in a National Geographic Photo Camp?</b></p>
<p><b>Bo:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I cannot say enough about how hugely important to me it is to have been part of a Nat Geo program. I got a hat and I am never going to stop wearing it. My dad was a documentary filmmaker for Nat Geo so growing up with that it’s super special to me to get to wear that hat is a super big honor for me.</span></p>
<p><b>Kennedy:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The Nat Geo experience was super special to me to be able to reignite my love of photography with some of the most incredible mentors we could have asked for was an experience I will truly never forget. I was afraid that afterward, we would graduate and never talk again, but the mentors said they wanted to keep in touch and we kept a group chat with the participants. I am truly honored and thankful and now I see the world in frames and stories.</span></p>
<p><b>Damien:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It was the coolest thing ever that I could say to someone. I was nervous there would be an attitude that there is one way to do the art but it was nothing like I imagined it would be because it was so independent and inspiring. The mentors helped us get to where we wanted to go and it was incredible.</span></p>
<p><b>Tara: My last question is about the future. Are you going to follow this photography bud of inspiration from this camp? What’s going to happen as a result of this camp?</b></p>
<p><b>Damien:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I am going to try to take photos of deep sky nebulas and work with NASA imaging to create my images and share them.</span></p>
<p><b>Bo:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I think that I am going to spend the rest of my life diving. I can’t say for sure all the things I am going to do but I know they will be in the ocean. I will take what I have learned and there is space to document the field of diving I’ll be in. </span></p>
<p><b>Kennedy: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I want to get started on a personal project. I don’t know what it will be yet but I do think it will relate to African ancestry. I think taking a trip to Africa with my family would be very powerful to capture the stories I was never taught, to inspire me and those that are also curious. For the rest of my life, I am never going to stop taking photos and will never stop doing personal projects because I really enjoy it.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">National Geographic Photo Camp is a photography learning experience for young people from under-resourced communities around the world. The goal of the program is to provide a meaningful introduction to photography and photojournalism that will inspire the next generation of storytellers, and empower them to share their experiences and perspectives. With instruction and guidance from world-class National Geographic Explorers and photographers, students build skills and confidence, explore the world around them, and develop deep connections with each other.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about Photo Camp </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.org/projects/photo-camp/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/19/students-reflect-on-photo-camp-experience-with-national-geographic-explorer-tara-roberts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216479</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the 2022 Fulbright-National Geographic Storytelling Fellow Cohort</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/04/meet-the-2022-fulbright-national-geographic-storytelling-fellow-cohort/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=meet-the-2022-fulbright-national-geographic-storytelling-fellow-cohort</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/04/meet-the-2022-fulbright-national-geographic-storytelling-fellow-cohort/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chelsey Perry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 19:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Our Explorers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs and the National Geographic Society announced today the selection of the 2022 Fulbright-National Geographic Storytelling Fellows. Chosen through a merit-based and highly competitive process, these U.S. Fulbright Students and National Geographic Explorers will travel overseas and undertake an in-depth exploration of globally relevant issues...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs and the National Geographic Society announced today the selection of the 2022 Fulbright-National Geographic Storytelling Fellows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chosen through a merit-based and highly competitive process, these U.S. Fulbright Students and National Geographic Explorers will travel overseas and undertake an in-depth exploration of globally relevant issues using a variety of digital storytelling tools and media — including blogs, photography, video, and social media — with support and mentorship from National Geographic Society staff and its global community of National Geographic Explorers. These individuals will craft stories to be shared and amplified through National Geographic’s digital platforms, and act as a powerful resource in building lasting ties across cultures. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This year’s Explorers include:</span></p>
<p><b>Sierra Garcia, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honduras</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sierra Garcia is an environmental writer, science educator, and interdisciplinary social-marine scientist. She will travel to Roatán, a Caribbean island off the coast of Honduras, to write in-depth articles about coral reef restoration efforts on the island. Through this work, she hopes to capture the motivations and strategies of the island’s residents who devote themselves to these efforts.</span></p>
<p><b>Alexandra Lenore Ashworth, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Philippines</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alexandra Ashworth (she/they) is a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">filmmaker and writer exploring community, belonging, and identity from a communal lens. They plan to work alongside local researchers and community leaders in the Philippines&#8217; Cagayan Valley to help preserve Ibanag and Itawit cultures. They will produce a collection of short documentary films as a record for future generations and an antithesis to monolithic perceptions of Filipino-ness and Asian-ness. </span></p>
<p><b>DeAnna Boyer, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ireland</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">DeAnna Boyer will travel to Ireland where she will explore interdisciplinary methods of land preservation and learn how the history of Ireland&#8217;s culture is currently affecting and shifting the ecological biodiversity of its unique landscapes. As a visual development artist, she will use illustrations, paintings, writings, and videos to document this relationship between people and their environment.</span></p>
<p><b>Sophie Dia Pegrum, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kyrgyzstan</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sophie Dia Pegrum plans to capture and contextualize the experiences of a group of young women scientists aiming to launch Kyrgyzstan’s first satellite. Exploring a creative register to evocatively document their hard-won ingenuity, Sophie’s final film hopes to ignite questions around the valorization of the androcentric body in technology, while underscoring the inspiring deeds of this diverse group as they forge toward a unique moment of their own accomplishment.</span></p>
<p><b>Natachi Onwuamaegbu, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kenya</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Natachi Onwuamaegbu is a journalist who plans to interview hair braiders of Nairobi’s Kenyatta market who make their living doing the hair of tourists and locals. She is interested in exploring the intersection of Black womanhood and survival, specifically in Kenyatta market — a place for Kenyan women to find economic liberation and economic entrapment. Her work will shed light on these women’s impossibly low wages, lack of health care, and no job security. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> —</span></p>
<p><b>ABOUT THE FULBRIGHT PROGRAM</b></p>
<p>The Fulbright Program, the U.S. Department of State’s flagship international exchange program, <a href="http://www.fulbright75.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.fulbright75.org/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1659721915723000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3IycxdRpQkAS4zuLQTAIjt">celebrated its 75th anniversary</a> in 2021. Since its inception in 1946, the Fulbright Program has provided over 400,000 talented and accomplished students, scholars, artists, and professionals of all backgrounds and fields the opportunity to study, teach, and conduct research, exchange ideas, and contribute to finding solutions to complex global challenges. The Fulbright-National Geographic Storytelling Fellowship launched in 2013 as a partnership between the U.S. Department of State and the National Geographic Society. For further information about the Fulbright Program or the U.S. Department of State, please visit <a href="http://eca.state.gov/fulbright" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://eca.state.gov/fulbright&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1659721915723000&amp;usg=AOvVaw25uvHEuFa8yCMFFnbQfwyf">http://eca.state.gov/fulbright</a> or contact the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs Press Office by e-mail: <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a><span class="m_-5482955275706566488MsoHyperlink">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/04/meet-the-2022-fulbright-national-geographic-storytelling-fellow-cohort/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216473</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Geographic Okavango Wilderness Project to Launch Two Expeditions Simultaneously for its Annual Okavango Delta Crossing</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/04/national-geographic-okavango-wilderness-project-to-launch-two-expeditions-simultaneously-for-its-annual-okavango-delta-crossing/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=national-geographic-okavango-wilderness-project-to-launch-two-expeditions-simultaneously-for-its-annual-okavango-delta-crossing</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/04/national-geographic-okavango-wilderness-project-to-launch-two-expeditions-simultaneously-for-its-annual-okavango-delta-crossing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Price]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 04:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expeditions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Geographic Okavango Wilderness Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okavango Delta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year’s expedition to follow two separate routes, focusing on procedural science and gathering traditional knowledge and island names BOTSWANA &#8211; The National Geographic Okavango Wilderness Project (NGOWP) today launched its annual crossing of the Okavango Delta in Botswana, which will run until early September. This is the first time NGOWP will be launching two...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b><i>This year’s expedition to follow two separate routes, focusing on procedural science and gathering traditional knowledge and island names </i></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BOTSWANA &#8211; The National Geographic Okavango Wilderness Project (NGOWP) today launched its annual crossing of the Okavango Delta in Botswana, which will run until early September. This is the first time NGOWP will be launching two expedition routes simultaneously: an eastern route, from Seronga to Daonara, and a western route, from Mopiri to Maun. The NGOWP expedition team has been crossing the Delta since 2010.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to the expedition’s core goal &#8211; collecting baseline data to compare ecosystem health year after year &#8211; the NGOWP expedition team will also document traditional place and island names, with the aim of creating traditional language and place name maps. This effort will be led by local Batswana storytellers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Okavango Delta, is one of the most biodiverse places in Africa and was designated the 1,000th UNESCO World Heritage site. Every year, the NGOWP completes annual transects to build a better scientific picture of the Delta and its source waters in Angola, which are not formally protected. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The NGOWP team will be collecting data on biodiversity, human impacts, hydrology, and ecological health by repeating previous surveys, as well as introducing new cutting-edge monitoring methodologies.  Every year, the team adds to the data already collected; having this baseline allows the team to compare results, and detect ecosystem disturbances that otherwise might go unnoticed. In addition to routine monitoring of water quality, other scientific activities include sampling environmental DNA; geo-tagging all bird, livestock, and wildlife sightings; and recording habitat soundscapes at night. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Okavango Delta crossings are our annual check-ups on the health of this remote and wild landscape. We must continually monitor and react to ecosystem changes, because the water security of a million people and the world’s largest-remaining elephant population depends on it,” said Dr. Steve Boyes, National Geographic Explorer and director of the National Geographic Okavango Wilderness Project. “Guided by respecting our elders and their knowledge, on this expedition we will be listening as much as we can to learn the names of the islands, the history, and the traditions, because this must become what everyone knows of the Okavango Delta.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This year’s western route will have a specific focus on engaging with local communities to gather traditional knowledge and place names, which are part of an oral tradition of geographic knowledge that has been passed down for generations. These efforts will inform a local language map that reflects these culturally significant and sacred sites and aims to preserve these oral traditions for future generations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Delta’s Indigenous People and local communities, along with their cultural diversity and traditional knowledge, are what makes this ecosystem special. Documenting their knowledge is an important part of honoring the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">conservation practices they’ve been doing for centuries,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">” said Thalefang Charles, renowned journalist from Botswana who will be leading storytelling efforts for the Western expedition route. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Merging traditional knowledge with modern scientific research gives us the best chance in safeguarding the greater Okavango Basin’s life-giving waters, its abundance of wildlife, and some of the most ancient cultures on our planet.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h6><b>CONTACT NGS COMMUNICATIONS TEAM</b></h6>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are a member of the media with an inquiry or interview request, please call during regular business hours or email</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">pressroom@ngs.org</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(202) 857 7027</span></p>
<h6><b>STEPH MICELI</b></h6>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Senior Manager, Impact Communications</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">smiceli@ngs.org</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/04/national-geographic-okavango-wilderness-project-to-launch-two-expeditions-simultaneously-for-its-annual-okavango-delta-crossing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216470</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Highest Weather Station in the Tropical Andes Installed Near the Summit of Nevado Ausangate in Peru</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/03/highest-weather-station-in-the-tropical-andes-installed-near-the-summit-of-nevado-ausangate-in-peru/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=highest-weather-station-in-the-tropical-andes-installed-near-the-summit-of-nevado-ausangate-in-peru</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/03/highest-weather-station-in-the-tropical-andes-installed-near-the-summit-of-nevado-ausangate-in-peru/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dolly Maiah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 11:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington, D.C. (August 3, 2022) Today, the National Geographic Society announced the placement of a weather station just below the summit of the Nevado Ausangate at 6,349m/ 20,830ft — now the highest weather station in the tropical Andes. This effort marks a significant milestone in the 2022 National Geographic and Rolex Amazon Perpetual Planet Expedition,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Washington, D.C.</strong> <strong>(August 3, 2022) </strong>Today, the National Geographic Society announced the placement of a weather station just below the summit of the Nevado </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ausangat</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">e at 6,349m/ 20,830ft — now the highest weather station in the tropical Andes. This effort marks a significant milestone in the </span><a href="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/04/12/national-geographic-society-launches-groundbreaking-multi-year-expedition-of-the-amazon-river-basin-with-the-support-of-the-rolex-perpetual-planet-initiative/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2022 National Geographic and Rolex Amazon Perpetual Planet Expedition</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a two-year exploration of the Amazon River Basin spanning the Andes to the Atlantic.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The tropical high Andes of southern Peru contain essential water towers that support nature and human communities from the glacier margins to the Amazon basin. On July 25th, National Geographic Explorers Baker Perry and Tom Matthews, supported by a local Peruvian Quechua team and female Bolivian climbing experts “the Cholitas Escaladoras&#8221; worked together to climb Nevado Ausangate – the highest peak in southern Peru – to investigate important meteorological processes driving the climate and glacier behavior and to install a weather station near its peak.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Nevado Ausangate is one of the most critical mountains in the high Andes as it serves as the primary freshwater source for Andean and downstream ecosystems,” said Perry. “It is essential that we use weather observations from the highest peaks in the world to better understand the impacts that climate change is having on local and global communities. The changes happening on Ausangate are especially important in understanding the fluctuations and adaptations of the entire Amazon River Watershed.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new weather station collects near real-time meteorological data such as temperature, precipitation, humidity, radiation, and snow depth, all of which will aid local governments and the international scientific community in observing the impacts of climate change on critical water resources that affect local communities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The expedition team also conducted in-situ monitoring of the atmosphere and analyzed snow-pack properties, obtaining direct measurements of snow water equivalent from the snow-pack. As part of the snow assessment, the team collected samples to screen for microplastics in this remote and relatively pristine region. If present, it would likely indicate long distance atmospheric transport &#8211; microplastics carried by winds from far away. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Local organizations and institutions including Universidad Nacional de San Antonio de Abad del Cusco (UNSAAC), Servicio Nacional de Meteorología e Hidrología (SENAMHI) del Perú and Universidad Mayor de San Andrés (Bolivia) were critical partners in this expedition. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">​​&#8221;The Nevado Ausangate is the source of life that we have for this region of Cusco,&#8221; said Santos Huaman, Mayor of Chilca, the Peruvian township encompassing much of the Ausangate Valley. “This new weather station will help us to understand how much snow is melting, why, and how we recover it. It’s extremely important to our community.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">National Geographic Explorer Ruthmery Pillco joined Perry and Matthews for part of the expedition to examine the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">headwaters in Ausangate and investigate how they impact the cloud forest where her research on </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andean bears takes place. The team was also joined by National Geographic Explorer and Photographer Tom Peschak who documented their efforts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The collaboration between Explorers to study all facets of the Amazon River Basin is critical to deepen our understanding of the Amazon’s dynamic environment,” said Nicole Alexiev, Vice President of Science and Innovation Programs at National Geographic Society. “Efforts like Baker, Tom and Ruth’s to study Ausangate’s critical ecosystem, coupled with Tom Peschak’s unparalleled storytelling are at the forefront of our partnership with Rolex. Our ultimate goal is to uniquely illuminate the critically important role this region plays in stabilizing the health of the planet while elevating solutions to ensure its protection.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Nevado Ausangate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> weather station complements the </span><a href="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2021/04/26/highest-weather-station-in-the-southern-and-western-hemispheres-installed-near-the-summit-of-tupungato-volcano-in-chile/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">highest weather station installed in the southern and western hemispheres near the summit of the Tupungato Volcano in Chile</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The combination of the two stations provide critical data to study climate-glacier interactions in the accumulation zone and characterize the extreme climate at the highest elevations in the Andes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This work builds upon previous Perpetual Planet Expeditions to install weather stations in high mountain environments, including to Mt. Logan in 2022 as well as to Mt. Everest in 2019 and 2022, both of which were led by Perry and Matthews. Rolex supports these expeditions as part of its Perpetual Planet initiative. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To learn more about Perpetual Planet Expeditions visit: </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/topic/perpetual-planet"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/topic/perpetual-planet</span></a></p>
<p><strong>Media Kit</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/d9o8vwgp74adsg4/AAAorTE9FgqetFrMAIjqoEEia?dl=0">Images </a></p>
<p>###</p>
<p><b>ABOUT PERPETUAL PLANET EXPEDITIONS </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The National Geographic and Rolex partnership supports expeditions to explore the planet’s most critical environments. By harnessing world-renowned scientific expertise and cutting-edge technology that reveal new insights about the systems that are vital to life on Earth, these expeditions help scientists, decision-makers, and local communities plan for and find solutions to the impacts of climate and environmental change while illuminating the wonder of our world through impactful storytelling.</span></p>
<p><b>ABOUT ROLEX’S PERPETUAL PLANET INITIATIVE  </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For nearly a century, Rolex has supported pioneering explorers pushing back the boundaries of human endeavour. The company has moved from championing exploration for the sake of discovery to protecting the planet, committing for the long term to support individuals and organizations using science to understand and devise solutions to today’s environmental challenges.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This engagement was reinforced with the launch of the Perpetual Planet initiative in 2019, which initially focused on individuals who contribute to a better world through the Rolex Awards for Enterprise, on safeguarding the oceans through a partnership with Mission Blue, and on understanding climate change as part of its association with the National Geographic Society.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An expanding portfolio of other partnerships embraced by the Perpetual Planet initiative now include: the Under The Pole expeditions, pushing the boundaries of underwater exploration; the One Ocean Foundation and Menkab, both protecting cetacean biodiversity in the Mediterranean; the Xunaan-Ha Expedition, shedding light on water quality in Yucatán, Mexico; the B.I.G expedition to the North Pole in 2023, gathering data on threats to the Arctic; Hearts In The Ice, also collecting climate change information in the Arctic; the Monaco Blue Initiative that brings together experts on solutions for ocean conservation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rolex also supports organizations and initiatives fostering the next generations of explorers, scientists and conservationists through scholarships and grants such as Our World-Underwater Scholarship Society and The Rolex Explorers Club Grants. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/03/highest-weather-station-in-the-tropical-andes-installed-near-the-summit-of-nevado-ausangate-in-peru/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216456</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>La estación meteorológica más alta de los Andes tropicales instalada cerca de la cumbre del nevado Ausangate en Perú</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/03/la-estacion-meteorologica-mas-alta-de-los-andes-tropicales-instalada-cerca-de-la-cumbre-del-nevado-ausangate-en-peru/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=la-estacion-meteorologica-mas-alta-de-los-andes-tropicales-instalada-cerca-de-la-cumbre-del-nevado-ausangate-en-peru</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/03/la-estacion-meteorologica-mas-alta-de-los-andes-tropicales-instalada-cerca-de-la-cumbre-del-nevado-ausangate-en-peru/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dolly Maiah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 11:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington, D.C., 3 de agosto de 2022.- Hoy, National Geographic Society anunció la instalación de una estación meteorológica justo debajo de la cumbre del nevado Ausangate a 6.349 metros, que es la más alta de los Andes tropicales. Este esfuerzo constituye un hito para la expedición Perpetual Planet a la Amazonía de National Geographic y...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Washington, D.C., 3 de agosto de 2022.-</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Hoy, National Geographic Society anunció la instalación de una estación meteorológica justo debajo de la cumbre del nevado </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ausangat</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">e a 6.349 metros, que es la más alta de los Andes tropicales. Este esfuerzo constituye un hito para la </span><a href="https://www.disneylapresspack.com/corporate/post/13999"><span style="font-weight: 400;">expedición </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perpetual Planet</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a la Amazonía de National Geographic y Rolex 2022</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, una exploración de dos años por la cuenca de la Amazonía que irá desde los Andes hasta el Atlántico.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Los altos Andes tropicales del sur de Perú contienen importantes torres de agua que sustentan a la naturaleza y comunidades locales desde los glaciares hasta la cuenca de la Amazonía. El 25 de julio, los Exploradores de National Geographic Baker Perry y Tom Matthews, con apoyo de un equipo Quechua de Perú y de expertas en escalada bolivianas “las Cholitas Escaladoras”, trabajaron para escalar el nevado Ausangate, el pico más alto del sur de Perú, para investigar los procesos meteorológicos que determinan el clima y el comportamiento de los glaciares, y para instalar una estación meteorológica cerca de su pico.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“El nevado Ausangate es una de las montañas más importantes en los altos Andes ya que funciona como principal fuente de agua dulce para los ecosistemas andinos y de aguas abajo”, dijo Perry. “Es indispensable que usemos observaciones meteorológicas provenientes de los picos más altos del mundo para comprender mejor los impactos del cambio climático sobre las comunidades locales y globales. Los cambios que suceden en el Ausangate son especialmente importantes para comprender las fluctuaciones y adaptaciones de toda la cuenca de la Amazonía”.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">La nueva estación meteorológica recopila datos meteorológicos casi en tiempo real, tales como la temperatura, precipitación, humedad, radiación y profundidad de la nieve. Todo esto ayudará a los gobiernos locales y a la comunidad científica internacional a observar los impactos del cambio climático sobre los importantes recursos de agua que afectan a las comunidades locales. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">El equipo de expedición también realizó una supervisión </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">in-situ</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> de la atmósfera y analizó las propiedades de las acumulaciones de nieve, y obtuvo medidas directas del agua de nieve de estas acumulaciones. Como parte de la evaluación de la nieve, el equipo recogió muestras para detectar microplásticos en esta remota región que aún se considera relativamente prístina. Si se detectan, de seguro indicaría un transporte atmosférico a larga distancia, es decir microplásticos que han sido transportados por vientos lejanos.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span lang="ES-TRAD">Organizaciones e instituciones locales como la</span> Universidad Nacional de San Antonio de Abad del Cusco (UNSAAC), <span lang="ES-TRAD">el </span>Servicio Nacional de Meteorología e Hidrología (SENAMHI) del Perú <span lang="ES-TRAD">y la</span> Universidad Mayor de San Andrés (Bolivia) <span lang="ES-TRAD">fueron socios claves en esta expedición.</span> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“El Nevado Ausangate es la fuente de vida que tenemos para esta región de Cusco”, dijo Santos Huaman, alcalde de Chilca, el municipio más cercano al Valle del Ausangate. &#8220;Esta nueva estación meteorológica nos ayudará a entender cuánta nieve se derrite, por qué y cómo la recuperamos. Es muy importante para nuestra comunidad”, agregó.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">La Exploradora de National Geographic Ruthmery Pillco se unió a Perry y Matthews durante parte de la expedición para examinar las </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cabecera de la cuenca en el Ausangate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, y para investigar cómo estas afectan el bosque nuboso donde se lleva a cabo su investigación sobre </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">osos andinos. También se unió al equipo el Explorador y fotógrafo de National Geographic Tom Peschak, quién documentó sus esfuerzos como parte de la narrativa visual de la expedición </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perpetual Planet</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a la Amazonía. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“La colaboración entre Exploradores para estudiar todas las facetas de la cuenca de la Amazonía es fundamental para profundizar nuestra comprensión del entorno dinámico del Amazonas”, dijo Nicole Alexiev, Vicepresidente de los Programas de Ciencias e Innovación de National Geographic Society. “Esfuerzos como los de Baker, Tom y Ruth para estudiar el importante ecosistema de Ausangate, junto con la narración inigualable de Tom Peschak están a la vanguardia de nuestra alianza con Rolex. Nuestro objetivo final es ilustrar de manera única el papel tan importante que esta región desempeña en la estabilización de la salud del Planeta, mientras se elevan soluciones para garantizar su protección”.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">La estación meteorológica</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> del nevado Ausangate complementa la estación meteorológica más alta instalada en los hemisferios sur y oeste cerca de la cumbre del volcán Tupungato en Chile. Las dos estaciones proporcionan datos fundamentales para estudiar las interacciones entre el clima y glaciar en la zona de acumulación, y caracterizar el clima extremo en las elevaciones más altas de los Andes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Este trabajo se basa en previas expediciones </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perpetual Planet</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> para instalar estaciones meteorológicas en entornos de alta montaña, incluidas expediciones al monte Logan en 2022 así como al monte Everest en 2019 y 2022, ambas guiadas por Perry and Matthews. Rolex apoya estas expediciones como parte de su iniciativa </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perpetual Planet</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Para saber más sobre las expediciones Perpetuatual Planet visite: <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/topic/perpetual-planet">https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/topic/perpetual-planet</a></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Media Kit</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/d9o8vwgp74adsg4/AAAorTE9FgqetFrMAIjqoEEia?dl=0">Images </a></p>
<p>###</p>
<p><strong>SOBRE LAS EXPEDICIONES PERPETUAL PLANET </strong></p>
<p>La alianza de National Geographic y Rolex apoya expediciones para explorar los entornos de importancia fundamental para el planeta. Al aprovechar una experiencia científica de renombre mundial y la tecnología de punta que revela nuevos conocimientos acerca de los sistemas esenciales para la vida en la Tierra, estas expediciones ayudan a los científicos, a los responsables de la toma de decisiones y a las comunidades locales a planificar y encontrar soluciones para los impactos del cambio climático y ambiental, al tiempo que despiertan el interés por nuestro mundo a través de historias impactantes.</p>
<p><strong>SOBRE LA INICIATIVA PERPETUAL PLANET DE ROLEX  </strong></p>
<p>Durante casi un siglo, Rolex ha apoyado a exploradores pioneros que desafían los límites del esfuerzo humano. La compañía ha pasado de defender la exploración en aras del descubrimiento a proteger el planeta, comprometiéndose a largo plazo a apoyar a las personas y organizaciones que utilizan la ciencia para comprender e idear soluciones a los desafíos ambientales de hoy.</p>
<p>Este compromiso se reforzó con el lanzamiento de la iniciativa Perpetual Planet en 2019, que inicialmente se centró en las personas que contribuyen a un mundo mejor a través de los Premios Rolex a la Iniciativa, sobre la protección de los océanos a través de una alianza con Mission Blue, y sobre la comprensión del cambio climático como parte de su asociación con National Geographic Society.</p>
<p>Una cartera en expansión de otras alianzas adoptadas por la iniciativa Perpetual Planet ahora incluye: las expediciones Under The Pole, que desafían los límites de la exploración submarina; One Ocean Foundation y Menkab, que protegen la biodiversidad de los cetáceos en el Mediterráneo; la expedición Xunaan-Ha, que arroja luz sobre la calidad del agua en Yucatán, México; la expedición Antes Que Sea Tarde (Before It&#8217;s Gone, B.I.G) en 2023, que recopilará datos sobre las amenazas al Ártico; Hearts In The Ice, que también recopila información sobre el cambio climático en el Ártico; la iniciativa Monaco Blue, que reúne a expertos en soluciones para la conservación de los océanos.</p>
<p>Rolex también apoya a organizaciones e iniciativas que fomentan las próximas generaciones de exploradores, científicos y conservacionistas a través de becas y subvenciones como Our World-Underwater Scholarship Society y The Rolex Explorers Club Grants.</p>
<p><strong>SOBRE NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC SOCIETY</strong></p>
<p>La National Geographic Society es una organización global sin fines de lucro que utiliza el poder de la ciencia, la exploración, la educación y la narración para ilustrar y proteger la maravilla de nuestro mundo. Desde 1888, National Geographic ha desafiado los límites de la exploración, invirtiendo en personas audaces e ideas transformadoras, proporcionando más de 15,000 becas para trabajar en los siete continentes, llegando a 3 millones de estudiantes cada año a través de ofertas educativas, y atrayendo a audiencias de todo el mundo a través de experiencias, historias y contenido distintivos. Para saber más, visite www.nationalgeographic.org o síganos en Instagram, Twitter y Facebook.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/08/03/la-estacion-meteorologica-mas-alta-de-los-andes-tropicales-instalada-cerca-de-la-cumbre-del-nevado-ausangate-en-peru/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216466</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spoon-billed sandpiper joins National Geographic Photo Ark as 13,000th Species</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/07/21/spoon-billed-sandpiper-joins-national-geographic-photo-ark-as-13000th-species/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=spoon-billed-sandpiper-joins-national-geographic-photo-ark-as-13000th-species</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/07/21/spoon-billed-sandpiper-joins-national-geographic-photo-ark-as-13000th-species/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karen Cumberland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 05:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Geographic Photo Ark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Ark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[July 21, 2022 – National Geographic Explorer Joel Sartore photographed the 13,000th species for the National Geographic Photo Ark, the spoon-billed sandpiper (Calidris pygmaea) known affectionately as the “spoonie,” at the Wildfowl &#38; Wetlands Trust (WWT) Slimbridge Wetland Centre in Gloucestershire, UK.  The spoon-billed sandpiper is a wading bird about the size of a small...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>July 21, 2022 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">– National Geographic Explorer </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/impact/article/joel-sartore-power-photography-conservation"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joel Sartore</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> photographed the <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/extremely-rare-bird-added-to-ark-of-imperiled-animals?loggedin=true">13,000th species</a> for the National Geographic Photo Ark, the spoon-billed sandpiper (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Calidris pygmaea</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">) known affectionately as the “spoonie,” at the </span><a href="https://www.wwt.org.uk/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wildfowl &amp; Wetlands Trust (WWT) Slimbridge Wetland Centre</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Gloucestershire, UK. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The spoon-billed sandpiper is a wading bird about the size of a small mouse and, as the name suggests, has a distinct spoon-shaped bill. It is listed as </span><a href="https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/22693452/154738156"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Critically Endangered on the IUCN Red List</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as their population has plummeted due to hunting, and reduced and degraded habitat. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The WWT took a leading role in efforts to buy time and reverse this trend, including a trial conservation breeding project at WWT headquarters. Although the future of the spoon-billed sandpiper remains uncertain, their efforts have led to significant advances in knowledge of incubation and rearing methods, and satellite tracking projects to identify stopover sites along the birds’ migration route. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Wildfowl &amp; Wetlands Trust Slimbridge is the only place in the world where the spoon-billed sandpiper exists in human care. Thanks to the overall conservation efforts of the team there, I had the unique opportunity to photograph the spoonie,” Sartore said. “I hope people see into the eyes of this bird and become inspired to take action to help save our planet&#8217;s unique species before it&#8217;s too late.” </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_216440" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-216440" style="width: 529px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-216440" src="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/DF2564C5-B630-4B57-A67E-9B3DC09A534C_1_201_a-720x514.jpeg" alt="" width="529" height="378" srcset="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/DF2564C5-B630-4B57-A67E-9B3DC09A534C_1_201_a-720x514.jpeg 720w, https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/DF2564C5-B630-4B57-A67E-9B3DC09A534C_1_201_a.jpeg 1040w" sizes="(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-216440" class="wp-caption-text">Joel Sartore, National Geographic Explorer and founder of the National Geographic Photo Ark, photographed the spoon-billed sandpiper (Calidris pygmaea) at the Wildfowl &amp; Wetlands Trust (WWT) Slimbridge in Gloucestershire, UK. Photo by Jodie Clements/Wildfowl &amp; Wetlands Trust.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to being home to the spoon-billed sandpiper and tens of millions of individuals of other species, wetlands also prevent flooding, store carbon and are vital for human health and wellbeing. WWT is dedicated to restoring and protecting these essential habitats. Learn more about WWT and support their conservation efforts </span><a href="https://www.wwt.org.uk/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Visit </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.org/projects/photo-ark/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NatGeo.org/Photo-Ark</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to learn more about the National Geographic Photo Ark, conservation, and protecting species. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/07/21/spoon-billed-sandpiper-joins-national-geographic-photo-ark-as-13000th-species/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216439</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Study: One of a Kind Freshwater Mangrove Forests Discovered in the Amazon Delta</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/07/20/new-study-one-of-a-kind-freshwater-mangrove-forests-discovered-in-the-amazon-delta/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-study-one-of-a-kind-freshwater-mangrove-forests-discovered-in-the-amazon-delta</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/07/20/new-study-one-of-a-kind-freshwater-mangrove-forests-discovered-in-the-amazon-delta/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dolly Maiah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington, D.C. (July 20, 2022) — Data from a new paper published today in Current Biology has identified a new phenomenon in the Brazilian coast: freshwater mangroves.  These unique freshwater mangroves were found along the Amazon Delta and provide proof of ecosystem adaptability to the Amazon river flow. This study is the first scientific finding...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Washington, D.C. (July 20, 2022</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">) — Data from </span><a href="https://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(22)01076-4"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a new paper published today</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Current Biology has identified a new phenomenon in the Brazilian coast: freshwater mangroves. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These unique freshwater mangroves were found along the Amazon Delta and provide proof of ecosystem adaptability to the Amazon river flow. This study is the first scientific finding published as part of the </span><a href="https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/04/12/national-geographic-society-launches-groundbreaking-multi-year-expedition-of-the-amazon-river-basin-with-the-support-of-the-rolex-perpetual-planet-initiative/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">National Geographic and Rolex Perpetual Planet Amazon Expedition</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a two-year exploration of the Amazon River Basin from the Andes to the Atlantic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From April 10 to April 27, 2022 National Geographic Explorers </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/impact/article/angelo-bernardino-explorer-story"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Angelo Bernardino</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and Thiago Silva conducted the first exploration of 11 mangrove forests along the Amazon delta. The Explorers analyzed data from the soil pore water, salinity, composition, tree density and volume using 3-D laser scanning from the ground and from drones. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The study shows that the Amazon river plume and high rainfall conditions allow the coexistence of a unique set of mangroves. These mangrove structures, which yield little to no salinity, have never been documented on deltas or coastal fringing mangroves anywhere in the world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bernardino and Silva also found that the sampled mangrove forests exhibited a one-of-a-kind structure in comparison to other mangroves that have been studied worldwide. Globally, very few mangroves have been found to thrive in such low-saline environments, and only one other site has reported estuarine mangroves growing in freshwater conditions.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result of their unique structure, these mangrove forests will likely provide distinct ecosystem functioning, carbon stocks, and support for related animal and plant species over their large expanse. The lower salinity may influence soil functions including pollutant retention, carbon sequestration, and greenhouse gas emissions. Additionally, the distinct soil properties of this coastal region further set the stage for the diverse plant species found in this atypical mangrove setting, which has not yet been observed in any other region of the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was phenomenal to see this type of freshwater flooded forests in this environment,” said Bernardino. “This discovery is critical to further understanding the intricacies of mangrove forests and how they are crucial to local communities that surround them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Findings from Bernardino and Silva’s research also signify the expansion of the existing mapped mangroves of the Amazon delta by nearly 20% with an additional 180 square kilometers. This research reveals the importance of field explorations on the Earth’s natural habitats, as existing satellite imagery had not detected mangroves in a significant area of the Amazon Delta.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Ecologically, mangroves provide a habitat for a diverse array of organisms. They are a natural laboratory for how we understand plants,” said Silva. “The findings from the 3-D terrestrial laser scanning allows us to see from aerial root density to tree height and volume, develop new methods to estimate carbon stocks, follow where the individual trees are, and even see underground channels of vegetation. It’s fascinating.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second phase of this research is currently underway in Pará, Brazil, where Bernardino and National Geographic Explorer Margaret Owuor will survey and document the economic and social value mangrove forests provide to Amazonian communities.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The expedition into the Brazilian mangrove forest and subsequent discovery of freshwater mangroves is critical to painting the full picture of the vast Amazon River Basin,” said Nicole Alexiev, Vice President of Science and Innovation at National Geographic Society. “Through the multi-year expedition of the Amazon supported by Rolex’s Perpetual Planet initiative, we will continue to gather new information about these critical ecosystems and how we can support solutions to ensure their protection. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To learn more about Perpetual Planet Expeditions visit: </span><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/topic/perpetual-planet"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/topic/perpetual-planet</span></a></p>
<p>###</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Media Tool Kit </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/wp1o3avs5q1knxn/AAB0Xfdq3owb39Z_LZLROcWya?dl=0"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Images</span></a></p>
<p><b>ABOUT PERPETUAL PLANET EXPEDITIONS </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The National Geographic and Rolex partnership supports expeditions to explore the planet’s most critical environments. By harnessing world-renowned scientific expertise and cutting-edge technology that reveal new insights about the systems that are vital to life on Earth, these expeditions help scientists, decision-makers, and local communities plan for and find solutions to the impacts of climate and environmental change while illuminating the wonder of our world through impactful storytelling.</span></p>
<p><b>ABOUT ROLEX’S PERPETUAL PLANET INITIATIVE  </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For nearly a century, Rolex has supported pioneering explorers pushing back the boundaries of human endeavour. The company has moved from championing exploration for the sake of discovery to protecting the planet, committing for the long term to support individuals and organizations using science to understand and devise solutions to today’s environmental challenges.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This engagement was reinforced with the launch of the Perpetual Planet initiative in 2019, which initially focused on individuals who contribute to a better world through the Rolex Awards for Enterprise, on safeguarding the oceans through a partnership with Mission Blue, and on understanding climate change as part of its association with the National Geographic Society.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An expanding portfolio of other partnerships embraced by the Perpetual Planet initiative now include: the Under The Pole expeditions, pushing the boundaries of underwater exploration; the One Ocean Foundation and Menkab, both protecting cetacean biodiversity in the Mediterranean; the Xunaan-Ha Expedition, shedding light on water quality in Yucatán, Mexico; the B.I.G expedition to the North Pole in 2023, gathering data on threats to the Arctic; Hearts In The Ice, also collecting climate change information in the Arctic; the Monaco Blue Initiative that brings together experts on solutions for ocean conservation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rolex also supports organizations and initiatives fostering the next generations of explorers, scientists and conservationists through scholarships and grants such as Our World-Underwater Scholarship Society and The Rolex Explorers Club Grants. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/07/20/new-study-one-of-a-kind-freshwater-mangrove-forests-discovered-in-the-amazon-delta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216438</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC DISTINGUE DOIS LÍDERES MUNDIAIS PELO SEU COMPROMISSO E AÇÃO EXCECIONAIS EM PROL DA PROTEÇÃO DO NOSSOS OCEANOS</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/a-national-geographic-distingue-dois-lideres-mundiais-pelo-seu-compromisso-e-acao-excecionais-em-prol-da-protecao-do-nossos-oceanos/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-national-geographic-distingue-dois-lideres-mundiais-pelo-seu-compromisso-e-acao-excecionais-em-prol-da-protecao-do-nossos-oceanos</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/a-national-geographic-distingue-dois-lideres-mundiais-pelo-seu-compromisso-e-acao-excecionais-em-prol-da-protecao-do-nossos-oceanos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dolly Maiah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Última hora: Lord Goldsmith anuncia que a coalizão que promove a meta global 30&#215;30 conta já com 100 países LISBOA, PORTUGAL (segunda-feira, 27 de junho de 2022) – O ex-presidente da Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada, e o presidente da Colômbia, Iván Duque Márquez, receberam, esta noite, o Prémio Liderança Planetária 2022, da Sociedade National...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Última hora: Lord Goldsmith anuncia que a coalizão que promove a meta global 30&#215;30 conta já com 100 países</strong></p>
<p>LISBOA, PORTUGAL (segunda-feira, 27 de junho de 2022) – O ex-presidente da Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada, e o presidente da Colômbia, Iván Duque Márquez, receberam, esta noite, o Prémio Liderança Planetária 2022, da Sociedade National Geographic, em reconhecimento do seu compromisso e ação excecionais em prol da proteção dos nossos oceanos, durante a Noite dos Oceanos da National Geographic, a decorrer no âmbito da Conferência dos Oceanos das Nações Unidas. O Prémio Liderança Planetária distingue líderes mundiais que tenham estabelecido, de forma eficaz, áreas protegidas globalmente significativas, tais como parques nacionais, áreas selvagens ou reservas marinhas, que ficam assim protegidas da exploração. Estas iniciativas ambiciosas empreendidas por líderes mundiais bem informados e motivados são essenciais para a construção de um futuro melhor para o nosso planeta. O Prémio Liderança Planetária já distinguiu o Primeiro Ministro do Canadá, Justin Trudeau, a ex-presidente do Chile, Michelle Bachelet, e os ex-presidentes das Seychelles Danny Faure e James Michel.</p>
<p>“Louvamos os compromissos assumidos pelos presidentes Alvarado e Duque de preservação da biodiversidade extraordinária dos seus países”, disse Jill Tiefenthaler, CEO da Sociedade National Geographic. “As suas palavras, decisões e ações são um exemplo de gestão e proteção do planeta, que ajudam a criar soluções eficazes e sustentáveis para os nossos oceanos.”</p>
<p>Atualmente, menos de 8% dos oceanos estão sob qualquer tipo de proteção legal e é necessário fazer mais para evitar a perda acelerada de biodiversidade e mitigar as mudanças climáticas. Os presidentes Alvarado e Duque têm sido líderes da meta global de proteção de, pelo menos, 30% da terra e do mar até 2030, conhecido como 30&#215;30, um objetivo que já alcançaram nas suas próprias águas, oito anos antes da meta estabelecido.</p>
<ul>
<li>O presidente Alvarado ampliou o Parque Nacional da Ilha dos Cocos, tendo multiplicado a sua dimensão 27 vezes, protegendo-o totalmente da pesca e de outras atividades prejudiciais. O parque, com um total de 54.000 quilómetros quadrados, situa-se ao redor da joia da coroa das águas da Costa Rica e inclui uma cadeia de montes submarinos ao longo da qual migram grandes predadores em vias de extinção, tais como tubarões. O presidente Alvarado designou também a Área Bicentenária de Gestão Marinha, que circunda o parque nacional já ampliado, alcançando assim o objetivo de colocar sob algum tipo de proteção 30% das águas marinhas da Costa Rica.</li>
<li>O presidente Duque ampliou o Santuário de Flora e Fauna de Malpelo, uma área <em>no take</em> (zonas delimitadas com proibição total de atividades extrativas como pesca e mineração), protegendo assim uma cordilheira submarina que abriga ecossistemas únicos de águas profundas e funciona como rota marinha para tubarões em vias de extinção. O presidente Duque designou também outra área no mar das Caraíbas e duas áreas de gestão marinha no Pacífico, alcançando assim a meta de alguma forma proteger 30% das águas marinhas da Colômbia.</li>
</ul>
<p>“Um oceano saudável é tão vital para o futuro da humanidade, como respirar é para cada um de nós, uma vez que o oceano gera pelo menos 50% do oxigénio da Terra e absorve um quarto das emissões de dióxido de carbono. Neste sentido, é necessário sermos ambiciosos quando se trata da proteção do oceano e da sua biodiversidade”, disse o ex-presidente da Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada. “A Costa Rica acredita na importância de liderar pelo exemplo e, nesse sentido, o meu governo foi copatrocinador da High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People e das metas 30&#215;30, juntamente com a França e o Reino Unido. E em dezembro passado assinei a ordem executiva para expandir da nossa proteção oceânica de 2,7 para 31% de uma só vez. A humanidade tem a oportunidade e responsabilidade de promover um oceano resiliente e saudável. Vamos a isso!”</p>
<p>“Estamos muito pero de atingir o limite, estabelecido no Acordo de Paris, de aumento global da temperatura de 1,5 graus. As alterações climáticas são uma realidade incontornável e constituem uma ameaça ao nosso futuro. É por essa razão que a Colômbia decidiu agir e integrar a High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People”, disse o presidente da Colômbia, Iván Duque Márquez. “Até agosto deste ano, 30% do nosso território nacional será declarado área protegida, 8 anos antes da meta a nível global. Não vamos esperar até 2030 para alcança-la. Até ao fim do ano, 17 milhões de hectares marinhos farão parte do nosso sistema de áreas protegidas. Começamos com a expedição à cordilheira da Beata e com a declaração da Ilha Ají enquanto área protegida. O nosso compromisso é inevitável. Não há planeta B. É nosso dever moral agir agora. Vamos fazê-lo juntos!”</p>
<p>O Lord Goldsmith, Ministro do Pacífico e do Meio Ambiente no Gabinete de Negócios Estrangeiros, Commonwealth e Desenvolvimento (FCDO) e no Departamento de Meio Ambiente, Alimentação e Assuntos Rurais (Defra) do Reino Unido, anunciou na mesma noite que já 100 países se juntaram à <a href="https://www.hacfornatureandpeople.org/home">High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People</a>, uma coalizão intergovernamental de países, co-presidida pela Costa Rica e França, com o Reino Unido com a função de co-presidente dos oceanos, e que defende uma meta global de proteção de, pelo menos, 30% da terra e do mar até 2030. A meta 30&#215;30 é sustentada na evidência científica e visa conter a perda acelerada de espécies e proteger os seus habitats, em prol das pessoas, economias, biodiversidade e clima. A meta foi aprovada de forma generalizada e espera-se que venha a ser um marco fundamental de um acordo global de biodiversidade atualmente em negociação pela Convenção sobre a Diversidade Biológica (CDB).</p>
<p>“A Costa Rica, a França e o Reino Unido lançaram o desafio de criar uma coalizão de países que procuram proteger, pelo menos, 30% do planeta Terra até 2030”, disse Enric Sala, explorador residente da National Geographic e fundador do projeto Pristine Seas da National Geographic. “Aquilo que era um desafio aparentemente inalcançável constitui agora uma ambição comum; a coalizão já tem 100 países membros e continua a crescer. Nunca, na história da humanidade, estivemos tão perto de dar à natureza o espaço necessário para que possa prosperar. O nosso futuro depende da prevenção do colapso dos sistemas naturais que nos fornecem alimentos, água potável, ar puro e um clima estável, e é, por isso, necessário proteger adequadamente os ecossistemas naturais que os sustentam.”</p>
<p>O trabalho da National Geographic no âmbito dos oceanos visa explorar, compreender e conservar os sistemas marinhos e costeiros. As histórias que derivam dos nossos exploradores marítimos – e que são tão vastas como o próprio oceano – inspiram-nos a relacionarmo-nos com os oceanos e a trabalhar para encontrar soluções que os protejam. Desde 2008, o projeto Pristine Seas da National Geographic realizou 35 expedições e apoiou a criação de 26 áreas marinhas protegidas, cobrindo 6,5 milhões de quilómetros quadrados de oceano, o que corresponde a mais do dobro do tamanho da Índia. O projeto Pristine Seas realizou expedições à Costa Rica (2009 e 2019) e à Colômbia (2018 e 2021) para prestar aconselhamento durante a expansão do Parque Nacional da Ilha de Cocos e do Santuário de Malpelo, bem como a criação de novas áreas marinhas protegidas.</p>
<p><strong>Sobre a Sociedade National Geographic                 </strong></p>
<p>A Sociedade National Geographic é uma organização sem fins lucrativos de alcance global, que usa o poder da ciência, exploração, educação e da narrativa para informar e proteger as maravilhas do nosso mundo. Desde 1888, a National Geographic tem testado os limites da exploração, através do investimento em pessoas ousadas e ideias transformadoras, da atribuição de mais de 15.000 bolsas de financiamento nos sete continentes, de ofertas formativas que alcançam cerca de 3 milhões de estudantes anualmente e do envolvimento de diferentes públicos em todo o mundo, através de experiências-, histórias- e conteúdos-chave. Para saber mais, visite <a href="http://www.nationalgeographic.org">www.nationalgeographic.org</a> ou siga-nos no <a href="https://www.instagram.com/insidenatgeo/">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/InsideNatGeo">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/InsideNatGeo/">Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/a-national-geographic-distingue-dois-lideres-mundiais-pelo-seu-compromisso-e-acao-excecionais-em-prol-da-protecao-do-nossos-oceanos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216434</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC HONRA A DOS LÍDERES MUNDIALES POR SU SOBRESALIENTE COMPROMISO Y ACCIÓN PARA LA PROTECCIÓN DE NUESTRO OCÉANO</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/national-geographic-honra-a-dos-lideres-mundiales-por-su-sobresaliente-compromiso-y-accion-para-la-proteccion-de-nuestro-oceano/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=national-geographic-honra-a-dos-lideres-mundiales-por-su-sobresaliente-compromiso-y-accion-para-la-proteccion-de-nuestro-oceano</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/national-geographic-honra-a-dos-lideres-mundiales-por-su-sobresaliente-compromiso-y-accion-para-la-proteccion-de-nuestro-oceano/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dolly Maiah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 19:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Última Hora: El Rht Hon Lord Goldsmith anuncia que 100 países se han unido a una coalición que impulsa el objetivo global 30&#215;30 LISBOA, PORTUGAL (lunes, 27 de junio de 2022)&#8211;El expresidente de Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada, y el presidente de Colombia, Iván Duque Márquez, recibieron esta noche el Premio al Liderazgo Planetario 2022...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Última Hora: El Rht Hon Lord Goldsmith anuncia que 100 países se han unido a una coalición que impulsa el objetivo global 30&#215;30</strong></p>
<p>LISBOA, PORTUGAL (lunes, 27 de junio de 2022)&#8211;El expresidente de Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada, y el presidente de Colombia, Iván Duque Márquez, recibieron esta noche el Premio al Liderazgo Planetario 2022 de National Geographic Society, por su destacado compromiso y acción para proteger nuestro océano, durante la Noche de los Océanos de National Geographic, en la Conferencia de las Naciones Unidas sobre los Océanos. El Premio al Liderazgo Planetario honra a los líderes mundiales que han establecido con éxito áreas protegidas de importancia mundial, como parques nacionales, áreas silvestres o reservas marinas, que están protegidas de la explotación. Las acciones audaces de líderes mundiales informados e inspirados son vitales para construir un futuro mejor para nuestro planeta. Los ganadores anteriores del Premio al Liderazgo Planetario incluyen a Justin Trudeau, Primer Ministro de Canadá; Michelle Bachelet, Ex Presidenta de Chile; y los ex Presidentes de Seychelles, Danny Faure y James Michel.</p>
<p>“Elogiamos los compromisos del presidente Alvarado y el presidente Duque para preservar la notable biodiversidad de sus países”, dijo Jill Tiefenthaler, directora ejecutiva de National Geographic Society. “Sus palabras, decisiones y acciones ejemplifican la buena administración y protección planetaria, ayudando a crear soluciones sostenibles y de impacto para nuestro océano”.</p>
<p>Hoy en día, menos del 8 % de los océanos del mundo están bajo algún tipo de protección legal, y se necesita más para evitar la rápida pérdida de biodiversidad y mitigar el cambio climático. El presidente Alvarado y el presidente Duque han defendido el objetivo global de proteger al menos el 30 % de la tierra y océano para 2030, también conocido como 30&#215;30, y lo han implementado en sus propias aguas, con ocho años de anticipación.</p>
<ul>
<li>El presidente Alvarado amplió el Parque Nacional Isla del Coco en 27 veces su tamaño, protegiéndolo completamente de la pesca y otras actividades dañinas. El área totaliza 54.000 kilómetros cuadrados alrededor de la joya de la corona de las aguas de Costa Rica, incluida una cadena de montañas submarinas sobre las que migran grandes depredadores como los tiburones que son especies en peligro de extinción. También designó el Área Marina Administrada Bicentenaria, alrededor del parque nacional expandido, alcanzando la meta del 30 % de las aguas marinas de Costa Rica bajo algún tipo de protección.</li>
<li>El presidente Duque amplió el Santuario de Flora y Fauna de Malpelo, protegiendo una cadena montañosa submarina que alberga ecosistemas únicos de aguas profundas y actúa como una carretera marina para los tiburones en peligro de extinción. También designó otra área totalmente protegida en el Caribe y dos áreas marinas manejadas en el Pacífico, alcanzando la meta del 30 % de las aguas marinas de Colombia bajo algún tipo de protección.</li>
</ul>
<p>“Un océano saludable es tan vital para el futuro de la humanidad como la respiración lo es para todos y cada uno de nosotros, ya que genera al menos el 50 % del oxígeno de la Tierra y absorbe una cuarta parte de las emisiones de dióxido de carbono. Por lo tanto, debemos ser muy ambiciosos cuando se trata de proteger el océano y su biodiversidad”, dijo el expresidente de Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada. “Costa Rica cree en liderar con el ejemplo y, en consecuencia, mi Administración co-lanzó la Coalición de Alta Ambición por la Naturaleza y las Personas, y las metas 30&#215;30 junto con Francia y el Reino Unido. Y en diciembre pasado firmé la orden ejecutiva para ampliar la protección de nuestros océanos del 2,7 al 31 % de un solo golpe. La humanidad tiene la oportunidad y la responsabilidad de fomentar un océano resiliente y saludable. Vamos a hacerlo.&#8221;</p>
<p>“Nos estamos acercando peligrosamente al límite de temperatura global de 1,5 grados que establecimos en el Acuerdo de París. El cambio climático es una realidad y una amenaza para nuestro futuro. Por eso, Colombia decidió actuar y ser parte de la Coalición de Alta Ambición por la Naturaleza y las Personas”, anunció el presidente de Colombia, Iván Duque Márquez. “Antes de agosto de este año, el 30 % de nuestro territorio nacional será declarado área protegida, 8 años antes de la meta global. No esperaremos hasta 2030 para hacerlo. Este año 17 millones de hectáreas marinas serán parte de nuestro sistema de áreas protegidas. Ya comenzamos con la expedición a la Sierra de Beata y la declaratoria de la Isla Ají como área protegida. Nuestro compromiso es ineludible, no existe el planeta B. Nuestro deber moral es actuar ahora. Hagámoslo todos juntos”.</p>
<p>El Honorable Lord Goldsmith, Ministro para el Pacífico y el Medio Ambiente de la Oficina de Relaciones Exteriores, Commonwealth y Desarrollo (Foreign, Commonwealth &amp; Development Office, FCDO) y el Departamento de Medio Ambiente, Alimentación y Asuntos Rurales (Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, Defra) para el Reino Unido anunció la misma noche que 100 países se han unido a la <a href="https://www.hacfornatureandpeople.org/home">Coalición de Alta Ambición para la Naturaleza y los Pueblos</a>, un grupo intergubernamental de países, copresidido por Costa Rica y Francia, con el Reino Unido en calidad de co-presidente del Océano, defendiendo un objetivo global para proteger al menos el 30 % de la tierra y el océano del mundo para 2030. El objetivo 30&#215;30 basado en la ciencia tiene como propósito detener la pérdida acelerada de especies y proteger los hábitats por el bien de las personas, las economías, la biodiversidad y el clima. Ha sido respaldado ampliamente y se espera que sea la piedra angular de un acuerdo mundial sobre biodiversidad que actualmente está negociando el Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biológica (Convention on Biological Diversity, CDB).</p>
<p>&#8220;Costa Rica, Francia y el Reino Unido lanzaron un sueño salvaje: una coalición de países que apoyan la protección de al menos el 30% de nuestro planeta para 2030&#8221;, dijo Enric Sala, explorador residente de National Geographic y fundador de National Geographic Pristine Seas. “El sueño salvaje es ahora la corriente principal; la coalición tiene 100 países miembros &#8211; y está creciendo. Nunca antes en la historia de la humanidad hemos estado tan cerca de darle a la naturaleza el espacio que necesita para prosperar. Nuestro futuro depende de evitar el colapso de los sistemas naturales que nos proporcionan alimentos, agua limpia, aire limpio y un clima estable. Para preservar estos beneficios, debemos proteger lo suficiente el mundo natural para sostenerlos”.</p>
<p>La labor oceánica de National Geographic tiene como objetivo explorar, comprender y conservar los sistemas marinos y costeros. Tan vastas como el océano mismo, las historias que se derivan de nuestros Exploradores del océano nos inspiran a conectarnos con el océano y trabajar con miras a encontrar soluciones para protegerlo. Desde 2008, National Geographic Pristine Seas ha llevado a cabo 35 expediciones y ha apoyado la creación de 26 áreas marinas protegidas que cubren 6,5 millones de kilómetros cuadrados de océano. Esta es un área de más del doble del tamaño de la India. Pristine Seas realizó expediciones a Costa Rica (2009 y 2019) y Colombia (2018 y 2021) para fundamentar la expansión del Parque Nacional Isla del Coco y el Santuario de Malpelo, así como la creación de nuevas áreas marinas protegidas.</p>
<p><strong>Sobre National Geographic Society</strong></p>
<p>La National Geographic Society es una organización global sin fines de lucro que utiliza el poder de la ciencia, la exploración, la educación y la narración para iluminar y proteger la maravilla de nuestro mundo. Desde 1888, National Geographic ha ampliado los límites de la exploración, invirtiendo en personas audaces e ideas transformadoras, proporcionando más de 15.000 becas para trabajar en los siete continentes, llegando a 3 millones de estudiantes cada año a través de ofertas educativas, y atrayendo audiencias de todo el mundo a través de experiencias, historias y contenido característicos. Para más información, visite <a href="http://www.nationalgeographic.org">www.nationalgeographic.org</a> o síganos en <a href="https://www.instagram.com/insidenatgeo/">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/InsideNatGeo">Twitter</a> y <a href="https://www.facebook.com/InsideNatGeo/">Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/national-geographic-honra-a-dos-lideres-mundiales-por-su-sobresaliente-compromiso-y-accion-para-la-proteccion-de-nuestro-oceano/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216433</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Geographic Honors Two World Leaders for their Outstanding Commitment and Action Toward Protecting Our Ocean</title>
		<link>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/national-geographic-honors-two-world-leaders-for-their-outstanding-commitment-and-action-toward-protecting-our-ocean/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=national-geographic-honors-two-world-leaders-for-their-outstanding-commitment-and-action-toward-protecting-our-ocean</link>
					<comments>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/national-geographic-honors-two-world-leaders-for-their-outstanding-commitment-and-action-toward-protecting-our-ocean/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dolly Maiah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 19:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#PressRelease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/?p=216427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Breaking: The Rht Hon Lord Goldsmith announces 100 countries have now joined a coalition pushing for the global 30&#215;30 goal LISBON, PORTUGAL (Monday, June 27, 2022)—Former President of Costa Rica Carlos Alvarado Quesada and President of Colombia Iván Duque Márquez were awarded the 2022 Planetary Leadership Award by the National Geographic Society for their outstanding...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Breaking: The Rht Hon Lord Goldsmith announces 100 countries have now joined a coalition pushing for the global 30&#215;30 goal</strong></p>
<p>LISBON, PORTUGAL (Monday, June 27, 2022)—Former President of Costa Rica Carlos Alvarado Quesada and President of Colombia Iván Duque Márquez were awarded the 2022 Planetary Leadership Award by the National Geographic Society for their outstanding commitment and action toward protecting our ocean this evening at the National Geographic Ocean Night at the UN Ocean Conference. The Planetary Leadership Award honors world leaders who have successfully established globally significant protected areas, such as national parks, wilderness areas, or marine reserves, that are shielded from exploitation. The bold actions of informed and inspired global leaders are vital to building a better future for our planet. Previous winners of the Planetary Leadership Award include Justin Trudeau, Prime Minister of Canada; Michelle Bachelet, Former President of Chile; and Former Presidents of the Seychelles Danny Faure and James Michel.</p>
<p>“We commend the commitments of President Alvarado and President Duque to preserve the remarkable biodiversity of their countries,” said Jill Tiefenthaler, CEO of the National Geographic Society. “Their words, decisions, and actions exemplify planetary stewardship and protection, helping to create impactful, sustainable solutions for our ocean.”</p>
<p>Today, less than 8% of the world’s oceans are under any sort of legal protection, and more is needed to prevent rapid biodiversity loss and mitigate climate change. President Alvarado and President Duque have both championed the global target of protecting at least 30% of our lands and oceans by 2030, otherwise known as 30&#215;30, and have implemented it in their own waters, eight years early.</p>
<ul>
<li>President Alvarado expanded Cocos Island National Park by 27 times its size, fully protecting it from fishing and other damaging activities. The area totals 54,000 square kilometers around the jewel of the crown of Costa Rica&#8217;s waters, including a chain of seamounts along which endangered species of large predators such as sharks migrate. He also designated the Bicentennial Marine Managed Area, around the expanded national park, reaching the goal of 30% of Costa Rica’s marine waters under some kind of protection.</li>
<li>President Duque expanded the no-take Malpelo Sanctuary of Flora and Fauna, protecting an underwater mountain ridge that harbors unique deep-sea ecosystems and acts as a marine highway for endangered sharks. He also designated another fully protected area in the Caribbean, and two marine-managed areas in the Pacific, reaching the goal of 30% of Colombia’s marine waters under some kind of protection.</li>
</ul>
<p>“A healthy ocean is as vital to the future of humankind as breathing is to each and every one of us, since it generates at least 50% of the Earth&#8217;s oxygen and absorbs a quarter of carbon dioxide emissions. Thus, we need to be very ambitious when it comes to protecting the ocean and its biodiversity,” said Former President of Costa Rica, Carlos Alvarado Quesada. “Costa Rica believes in leading by example, and, accordingly, my Administration co-launched the High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People and the 30&#215;30 goals with France and the United Kingdom. And last December I signed the executive order to expand our ocean protection from 2.7 to 31% in one stroke. Humanity has the chance and the responsibility to foster a resilient and healthy ocean. Let’s do it.”</p>
<p>“We are getting dangerously close to the global temperature limit of 1.5 degrees, which we set in the Paris Agreement. Climate change is a reality and is a threat to our future. That is why Colombia decided to act and be part of the High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People,” said President of Colombia, Iván Duque Márquez. “Before August of this year, 30% of our national territory will be declared a protected area, 8 years before the global goal. We will not wait until 2030 to do so. This year 17 million marine hectares will be part of our system of protected areas. We have already begun with the expedition to the Beata mountain range and the declaration of the Ají Island as a protected area. Our commitment is unavoidable, there is no planet B. Our moral duty is to act now. Let&#8217;s do it all together.”</p>
<p>The Rt Hon Lord Goldsmith, Minister for Pacific and the Environment at the Foreign, Commonwealth &amp; Development Office (FCDO) and the Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (Defra) for the United Kingdom announced the same evening that 100 countries have now joined the High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People, an intergovernmental group of countries, co-chaired by Costa Rica and France, with the United Kingdom acting as Ocean co-chair, championing a global goal to protect at least 30% of the world&#8217;s land and ocean by 2030. The science-based 30&#215;30 target aims to halt the accelerating loss of species and protect habitats for the sake of people, economies, biodiversity and the climate. It has been endorsed extensively and is expected to be a cornerstone of a global biodiversity agreement currently under negotiation by the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD).</p>
<p>“Costa Rica, France and the UK launched a wild dream: a coalition of countries supporting the protection of at least 30% of our planet by 2030,” said Enric Sala, National Geographic Explorer in Residence and founder of National Geographic Pristine Seas. “The wild dream is now mainstream; the coalition has 100 member nations &#8211; and continues to grow. Never before in the history of humanity have we been so close to giving nature the space it needs to thrive. Our future depends on preventing the collapse of natural systems that provide our food, clean water, clean air and stable climate. To preserve these benefits, we must protect enough of the natural world to sustain them.”</p>
<p>National Geographic’s ocean work aims to explore, understand, and conserve marine and coastal systems. As vast as the ocean itself, the stories that derive from our ocean Explorers inspire us to connect with the ocean and work toward finding solutions to protect it. Since 2008, National Geographic Pristine Seas has carried out 35 expeditions and supported the creation of 26 marine protected areas covering 6.5 million square kilometers of ocean. This is an area more than twice the size of India. Pristine Seas conducted expeditions to both Costa Rica (2009 and 2019) and Colombia (2018 and 2021) to inform the expansion of Cocos Island National Park and the Malpelo Sanctuary, as well as the creation of new marine protected areas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://blog.nationalgeographic.org/2022/06/27/national-geographic-honors-two-world-leaders-for-their-outstanding-commitment-and-action-toward-protecting-our-ocean/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">216427</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>